Thank you, Chris. And it's a pleasure to
be here today. I'm so grateful. I had
really great conversations here. And I'm
so glad that you're all able to come. Let
me just quickly make one big point. And I
want to talk about digital identity as
critical infrastructure. So as Phil
Windley talked about earlier, the purpose
of a digital identity is to create a
trusted relationship online. And we used
to talk about with trust credentials that
was going to be like with identity and
access management systems, that you needed
something you know and something you have.
But that is becoming not sufficient. And
what we need is something you can prove.
And something you can prove is a
credential with cryptographic codes that
can verify both the holder and the issuer
of the credential. And I just want to
point out that this is actually new
territory for states to be leaning in to
this area where we are adding a state
endorsement to a relationship where it
hasn't really existed before. Yes, the
state has issued driver's licenses and
other credentials, lots of them, but the
online age changes the nature of these
things. Okay, so in the digital age where
so much of our lives have moved online
from social media, social banking,
commerce, application for government
services, where so much of our
relationships have moved online, this
identity, digital identity becomes
absolutely critical infrastructure.
There's so many public sector areas that
rely on this and we've seen in our country
since COVID hundreds of billions of
dollars in fraud and a lot of that fraud
is tied directly to not having good
identity verification. So, you know, for
at the state level, public social services
systems like food stamps or unemployment
insurance or housing assistance or
Medicaid or child health insurance. Many
of these rely on being able to identify
someone successfully. We have a lot of
discussion in our state about voter
registration and signature gathering and
petitions for citizen initiatives. Can we
do those digitally without having a true
digital identity? In the last legislative
session, one of our leading senators asked
me, what will it take to be able to do
online elections and will this help us do
it? And I told them, I know for darn sure
you can't do an online election without a
digital credential that is reliable and
trustworthy for identity. Professional
licenses and education credential and also
our corrections and public safety
interactions. Across the private sector,
we have a plethora of use cases as well
that that rely on secure online
infrastructure, whether it's verifying
proof of age online or in person, whether
it's accessing our health records and
benefits and also our financial
transactions. We have the know your
customer requirements in that area and
then we have many different online
commercial and travel related needs. But
we have a big problem. And so as part of
my organization, we have the state cyber
security center. And what we see is we're
constantly under attack. Our state systems
in Utah have about a billion and a half
scans per day of our system. And we have
numerous efforts by malicious actors
trying to create fraud, trying to create
ransomware attacks. And so what we see is
our infrastructure, especially our digital
infrastructure of all kinds, will be under
attack. And the point of attack, the
attack vector most often used, is
identity. And so because digital identity
is critical infrastructure, incomplete and
half measures with regard to the security
of these systems are not acceptable. We
have to have reciprocity between states,
but that also means that all states need
to have strong security around their
digital identity systems. We have to build
SEDI with the highest level of security
that is available. And we know that
nothing is perfect. So we need an ability
if compromise occurs, or I should say when
compromise occurs, we must have a way to
recover. So when we think about SEDI and
we think about keys, cryptographic keys
that are the backing that credential. What
I'm talking about for the technical person
and the technical people in the room is we
need a way to rotate those keys. One of
the concerns I have about the current MDL
technology is that we don't have a great
ability to recover if those are
compromised, you know, short of canceling
and reissuing credentials. So the ability
to revoke is important. The ability to
recover if it's compromised is essential.
Thank you so much. Glad you're here.
We could do this quickly like a pit stop,
right?
All righty.
They said wait 30 seconds. something